# Nikhil Rathod UX/UI Architect

## Personal Info

#### **Address**

F 102, Yuthika Apartment, Veerbhadra nagar, Baner, Pune

#### Phone

+91-8830820034

#### **Email**

nikhil.rathod@live.com

#### **Date of Birth**

1984-08-30

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikhilrathod-83a56740/

#### **Portfolio**

https://goo.gl/wo8k4q

## Skills

**UX** Research

Wireframing

HTML5 / CSS 3

Axure

Responsive Design

SEO Optimized UX / UI

Debugging

## Key Accomplishments and Goal

Goal-focused UX/UI Architect with over 11 years of experience; skilled in Axure, UX research, UI prototyping, wire-framing. Finished several projects in un-realistic deadlines, experience in debugging, designing of a complex design like itinerary planner with responsive designs to work till smaller devices like IPhone 4.

#### Triphobo.com (Joguru Technologies Pvt Ltd)

- Incorporated SEO elements based on GWT that boosted crawling of the pages from 150,000 to 1,700,000 as well as organic traffic to a considerable extent.
- Optimized code and reduced page-load time by 1.2 Sec.
- QA Training for testing UI, Google cache, Code Optimization.
- Finding and fixing of SEO errors which brought traffic down (Google web-view & Text-view)
- Appreciation from CEO for global event based themes for product. (Christmas, Tomatina, October fest etc.)

#### Diaspark Infotech Pvt Ltd

• Suggested an out of the box and Impressive design for which received appreciation from client.

#### Key Skills

UX Architect, User Experience, Axure, Wireframing, Prototyping, Usability Analysis, User Research, Storyboarding, Data Driven Design, Photoshop, Usability Testing, Interaction Design, Management, Cross Functional Coordination, Jira, CSS3, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, SASS, SEO Optimized Design, UX, UI

## Experience

#### 2014-07 to

#### **UX/UI Architect**

Present

triphobo.com ( Joguru Technologies Pvt Ltd )

- Wire-frames for new designs to be implemented.
- Complete design monitoring for user behavior and experience.
- Creating Ultra lite designs which will help page to load faster.
- Creating SEO Optimized UX / UI.
- Design strategies.
- Back-end creation and maintenance.
- Quick fixes for bugs on live product, if any.
- Developer training regarding pros and cons while handling HTML.
- Incorporation of most SEO friendly components based on GWT (Google Web Tool) documentation.
- Working on agile methodology and tools like JIRA and Mantis.
- Responsible for getting desired effects done on front-end using JS and Jquery.
- Responsible for getting ultra-lite Desktop as well as mobile design done.

## **UX/UI** Architect

# Areas of Expertise

- UX/UI Design
- Wireframes
- SEO Optimized UX / UI
- End to end project management
- Data Driven Design
- Usability Testing
- Prototyping
- User Research
- Storyboarding
- Cross Functional Coordination
- Jira
- Responsive Design
- Bootstrap
- SASS
- Google analytics
- Photoshop
- Usability Analysis
- Grid & Layout

2013-09 to 2014-05

## Sr. Web Designer

Diaspark Infotech Pvt Ltd

- Responsible for creative design and HTML Conversions.
- Worked on CSS libraries like Bootstrap.
- Worked in CSS and LESS
- Worked on projects based on SCALA.
- Worked on responsive designs with and without bootstrap.
- Jquery plugin integration and customization to an extent.
- · Agile methodology with JIRA.

2013-01 to

## **Multimedia Designer**

2013-08 Logicworks

- UX design based on discussions with client
- Fastest delivery of projects.
- Worked in CSS and LESS
- Optimized UI with best code to text ratio.
- Worked on responsive designs with and without bootstrap.
- Jquery plugin integration and customization to an extent.
- 3D Animations to demonstrate product assembly and function.

2008-04 to

## Web Designer / 3D Artist

2012-12

Soul 3D Animations

- Performed initial client assessment and analysis.
- Responsible for creative design for prominent Projects.
- UI designing for domestic as well as International projects.
- SEO compatible markup.
- End to end project management for domestic clients.

2007-03 to

#### **Training Manager**

2008-02

Mars Animation

- Implemented marketing strategies which resulted in 12% growth of Student base.
- Faculty training to keep them updated with new software versions released.
- Conducting specialization batches.
- Placement assistance to students post certification.

## Education

**Bachelor of Engineering (Mechanical)** 

Shivajidada Institute of Engineering and Technology